Haimanot Gobena

(703) 537-6282 | gobena.h@gmail.com | Alexandria, VA 22307



PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Detail-oriented problem solver with 460+ training hours and experience developing full stack Java applications. Interested in attaining a career that will allow me the opportunity to excel in software development as well as highlight my previous work experience and leadership abilities in retail management.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

W3Schools JavaScript Certification (in progress; expected date of completion 06/2021)

- Java
- JavaScript
- HTML
- CSS
- Spring Boot
- Spring Data JPA

- Spring Security (JWT)
- Bootstrap
- REST API's
- SQL
- Unit Testing (JUnit,

- Mockito)
- SOLID OOP Principles
- Dependencies Injection
- Git

EXPERIENCE

Generation Junior Full Stack Java Developer Program | May 2021- August 2021

Training Participant (in progress)

- Participating in a 16-week, 460+ hour Junior Full Stack Java Developer program that emphasizes hands-on practical application
- Learning and deploying the technologies involved in creating full stack web applications with Java using Spring Boot Framework, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3
- Implementing basic unit tests and deploying the application to Heroku

7-Eleven 2581-27822A | Woodbridge, VA | Dec 2009 - Current

Franchisee/Owner

- Provide excellent customer experience, including handling all customer complaints and feedback.
- Recruit, train and mentor customer and team focused clerks.
- Manage shift schedules and payroll.
- Order, receive and organize merchandise.
- Evaluate new products and facilitate returns as needed.
- Contact vendors and suppliers.
- Maintain store infrastructure and contact maintenance as needed.
- Manage the day to day cash flow.

Volunteer Service

Oromo Evangelical Church of Washington DC

 Church board member, 2022-Current, Children Sunday School teacher and provide support zoom and audio conference church services

EDUCATION

- Associate Degree, Information Technology (Systems Administration), Martin College, Perth, Western Australia, May 2002.
- BA, Political Science and International Relations, Addis Ababa University, Addis Ababa, Ethiopia July 1997